<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Geospatial Analytics</title>
<link>https://geospatial2023.netlify.app/Take_Home_Exercise/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://geospatial2023.netlify.app/Take_Home_Exercise/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description></description>
<image>
<url>https://geospatial2023.netlify.app/Images/logo.png</url>
<title>Geospatial Analytics</title>
<link>https://geospatial2023.netlify.app/Take_Home_Exercise/index.html</link>
<height>86</height>
<width>144</width>
</image>
<generator>quarto-1.3.433</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 16:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>1: Geospatial Analytics for Public Good</title>
  <dc:creator>Magdalene Chan</dc:creator>
  <link>https://geospatial2023.netlify.app/Take_Home_Exercise/Ex1/Take_home_Ex1.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="objectives" class="level1">
<h1>Objectives</h1>
<p>As city-wide urban infrastructures become increasingly digital, datasets from technologies like GPS and RFID on vehicles offer opportunities to track movement patterns over space and time. For instance, smart cards and GPS devices on public buses collect routes and ridership data, containing valuable structure and patterns for understanding human movement and behavior within cities. Yet, despite their potential, the practical use of these extensive location-aware datasets often remains limited to basic tracking and mapping within GIS applications due to the lack of comprehensive spatial and spatio-temporal analysis functions in conventional GIS tools.</p>
<p>Exploratory Spatial Data Analysis (ESDA) holds tremendous potential to address such complex problems. In this study, appropriate Local Indicators of Spatial Association (GLISA) and Emerging Hot Spot Analysis (EHSA) will be applied to undercover the spatial and spatio-temporal mobility patterns of public bus passengers in Singapore.</p>
</section>
<section id="tasks" class="level1">
<h1>Tasks</h1>
<p>The following tasks will be addressed in this exercise:</p>
<section id="geovisualisation-and-analysis" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="geovisualisation-and-analysis">Geovisualisation and Analysis</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li>Compute the passenger trips generated by origin at the hexagon level for the following time periods:
<ol type="1">
<li>Weekday morning peak (6am to 9am)</li>
<li>Weekday afternoon peak (5pm to 8pm)</li>
<li>Weekend/holiday morning peak (11am to 2pm)</li>
<li>Weekend/holiday evening peak (4pm to 7pm)</li>
</ol></li>
<li>Display the geographical distribution of the passenger trips by using appropriate geovisualisation methods.</li>
<li>Describe the spatial patterns revealed by the geovisualisation (not more than 200 words per visual).</li>
</ol>
<p>Local Indicators of Spatial Association (LISA) Analysis</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>Compute LISA of the passengers trips generate by origin at hexagon level. Display the LISA maps of the passengers trips generate by origin at hexagon level. The maps should only display the significant (i.e.&nbsp;p-value &lt; 0.05) With reference to the analysis results, draw statistical conclusions (not more than 200 words per visual). Emerging Hot Spot Analysis(EHSA) With reference to the passenger trips by origin at the hexagon level for the four time intervals given above:</li>
</ol>
<p>Perform Mann-Kendall Test by using the spatio-temporal local Gi* values, Prepared EHSA maps of the Gi* values of the passenger trips by origin at the hexagon level. The maps should only display the significant (i.e.&nbsp;p-value &lt; 0.05). With reference to the EHSA maps and data visualisation prepared, describe the spatial patterns reveled. (not more than 250 words per cluster).</p>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://geospatial2023.netlify.app/Take_Home_Exercise/Ex1/Take_home_Ex1.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Take Home Exercise 2</title>
  <dc:creator>Magdalene Chan</dc:creator>
  <link>https://geospatial2023.netlify.app/Take_Home_Exercise/Ex2/Take_home_Ex2.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p>Placeholder</p>



 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://geospatial2023.netlify.app/Take_Home_Exercise/Ex2/Take_home_Ex2.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 03:54:03 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
